<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="noData"><![CDATA[<html><style>body {background-color:white;color:black;} a {color:blue;}</style><body><table><tr><th>No data available yet.</th></tr><tr><td>To start the app for the first time, please go to <i>Settings</i> -> <i>Search</i> -> click on <i>Start</i>. </td></tr></table></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="das_kunstprojekt">The art project</string>
    <string name="this_project1">The memorial stones embedded in footpaths keep alive the memory of the victims of National Socialism - Jewish citizens, Sinti and Roma, politically persecuted people, homosexuals, Jehovah\'s Witnesses and victims of \'euthanasia\'.</string>
    <string name="this_project2">The Stolpersteine, which measure around ten by ten centimetres, are small brass plates with the names and dates of life of Nazi victims.\nThey are set into the pavement in front of the last known and freely chosen place of residence. The Stolpersteine are financed by private donations.</string>
    <string name="this_project3">Most recently, a total of 9 Stolpersteine were laid on 20 May 2019. There are now 262 stones in Kiel.</string>
    <string name="this_project4">However, the Sinti and Roma in Schleswig-Holstein reject Stolpersteine for their victims.\nIn Kiel, a memorial stone and an explanatory information board in Hiroshimapark opposite Lorentzendamm 36 commemorate their suffering instead.</string>

    <string name="die_stolpersteine">The stumbling blocks</string>
    <string name="this_stone1">The stones are concrete cubes measuring just under 10 cm cubes with a brass plate attached to their upper surface. In the brass plate are stamped with the names and dates of life of the victims and, where applicable, other information.</string>
    <string name="this_stone2">Each stone is individually handcrafted. This applies both to the casting of the concrete stone as well as the inscription on the brass plate and its attachment to the concrete block.\n Until 2005, the stones were produced by the artist Gunter Demnig himself.\Since then, they have been produced by the Berlin sculptor Michael Friedrichs-Friedländer in his Berlin sculptor Michael Friedrichs-Friedländer in his Berlin studio for Demnig[, who in 2017 alone was busy laying the stones 270 days a year laying the stones alone. Friedlaender produces around 500 Stolpersteine there every month.</string>
    <string name="this_stone3">The alleged ‘million-dollar business on the backs of the victims’ that critics sometimes accuse the artist of is sometimes criticised by critics, is quickly put into perspective when you consider that of the €120 that a Stumbling Stone costs is used to pay for materials, tools, shipping, organisation and the eight organisation and the project\'s eight employees.</string>
    <string name="this_stone4">There is also criticism from other quarters. For example Sinti and Roma in Schleswig–Holstein reject stumbling blocks for their victims because the stones could be stones could be trampled underfoot. That is why there is a special memorial stone for these victims in Hiroshima Park for these victims. For the same reason, Charlotte Knobloch, the president of the of the Jewish Community of Munich and Upper Bavaria and former President (2006–2010) of the Central Council of Jews of the Central Council of Jews, regards the stones as a degradation of the victims, while the current President of the Central Council Josef Schuster (since 2014) is in favour of the Stolperstein project.</string>
    <string name="this_artist1">Gunter Demnig (born 27 October 1947 in Berlin) is a German artist.   He became known for the Stolpersteine, which he has been laying since 1996 in memory of victims of the National Socialist era.></string>
    <string name="this_artist2">Demnig grew up in Nauen and Berlin.\nIn 1967, he graduated from high school and began studying art education at the Academy of Fine Arts in Berlin under Herbert Kaufmann.\nThis was followed in 1969/1970 by a year Industrial Design programme at the same university. From 1971, he continued his art education studies at the Kunsthochschule Kassel and passed his first state examination there in 1974.\nIn the same year, Demnig began studying art at the University of Kassel under Harry Kramer, followed by two years of work in the planning, construction management and realisation of monument renovations.\nFrom 1980 to 1985, Demnig was an artistic-scientific assistant in the Department of Art at the University of Kassel.</string>
    <string name="this_artist3">In 1985 Demnig opened his own studio in studio in Cologne and worked on several projects, including the Moltkerei workshop and the Fuhrwerkswaage art space.\nSince 1994, he has also worked at the IGNIS cultural centre.\nSince April 2011 Demnig\'s studio in Frechen was located in the Signalwerk art centre, which was built on the site of the former station of the Cologne-Frechen-Benzelrath railway. This is also where around 20 other artists known in the region also have their studios there. In 2017, he moved his studio to Elbenrod in Hesse.</string>
    <string name="this_artist4">Demnig became known for his Stumbling Stones, which he also lays himself. They are intended to commemorate people who fell victim to the Nazi dictatorship. The stones, which have small brass plates on the top with the names of the victims, are laid in the pavement in front of their former homes pavement.\nLaunched in 1996 and realised in 1,200 German municipalities by 2017, the project has been the largest decentralised memorial in the world and now counts 100,000 stones in 31 European countries (2023).\nThe copyright for the Stolpersteine in the broadest sense lies solely and exclusively with Gunter Demnig himself.\nA copyright actually created by Demnig must, however, be questioned in this respect: he was aware of the project         Names &amp; Stones, which was started in 1994 by Tom Fecht for the first AIDS victims in the pavements         in Bonn, Hamburg and Berlin (Invalidenstraße, in front of the Natural History Museum).\nThe names of the victims were and are chiselled into small square natural stones. However, Demnig can claim to have honoured the victims after modifying the form (stones with brass plate) and with new content (e.g. dates of life), Demnig can claim to have honoured the Holocaust victims throughout Germany and later worldwide.</string>
    <string name="beruf_und_werk">Profession and work</string>
    <string name="ausbildung">Education</string>
    <string name="willkommen">Welcome</string>
    <string name="start">start</string>
    <string name="suche">Search for stumbling blocks …</string>
    <string name="stolpersteine">stumbling blocks</string>
    <string name="Greeting_Description">To set up the app, data must first be generated.
        This can take some time, but is only necessary once to set up the app. The first step is to
        load information from the wiki. Then the geo-points for display on the map are determined
        from the addresses to which the stumbling blocks relate. If the action is successful,
        the map is displayed with all the information obtained. This process can be repeated individually in \"Search\".</string>
    <string name="Greeting_Description_short">To set up the app, data must first be generated.
        This can take some time, but is only necessary once to set up the app. Go to \"Search\" and start the search process.</string>
    <string name="die_suche_war_erfolgreich_">The search for Stolperstein was successful.\\nDespite this, search again?</string>
    <string name="setting">Settings</string>
    <string name="starte_die_suche">Start the search. Names and addresses for the stumbling blocks are being sought.</string>
    <string name="menu_name">The Names</string>
    <string name="close"><u>close</u></string>
    <string name="clear">clear</string>
    <string name="title">title</string>
    <string name="about">about …</string>
    <string name="coffee_for_me">coffee for me</string>
    <string name="search">search</string>
    <string name="settings">settings</string>
    <string name="contact_me">contact</string>
    <string name="welcome">welcome</string>
    <string name="m_chtest_du_den_standort_ermitteln">Want to find out your location? ‘Follow’ shows your location on the map. This only makes sense if you are in the city of Kiel or in the neighbourhood of Kiel. If you are not in Kiel, then use ‘No Follow’. This keeps the focus on the map of the city of Kiel.</string>
    <string name="location">location</string>
    <string name="follow">follow</string>
    <string name="nofollow">no follow</string>
    <string name="download_kml">download kml</string>
    <string name="kml_file_speichern">Save the data found as a KML file for sharing in downloads?</string>
    <string name="menu_karte">OSM Card</string>
    <string name="menu_artist">The Artist</string>
    <string name="menu_project">The Project</string>
    <string name="menu_stones">The stumbling blocks</string>
    <string name="this_app_is_for_android_8_and_higher">the location could not be identified this app is for android 8 and higher.</string>
    <string name="menu_setting">Settings</string>
    <string name="quelle_wikipedia">Source: https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunter_Demnig</string>
    <string name="source_github">Source-Code: https://github.com/Klaus-Thaler/Stolperstein</string>
    <string name="show_in_card">show in card</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="address">Address</string>
    <string name="born">born</string>
    <string name="death">died/deported</string>
    <string name="bio">Biografie</string>
    <string name="foto">Foto</string>
    <string name="map">Map</string>
    <string name="installed">installed</string>
    <string name="menu_search">Search</string>
</resources>